

## Jose María de la Cruz Sánchez

Telecommunications Engineer **Smart Contract developer** 

Spain

+34 699 19 05 83 

jmariadelacruzsanchez@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/jmariadls/ in

https://github.com/jmariadlcs

## Stack

**Smart Contract development** Solidity

Frameworks and deployment

Hardhat **Javascript** 

Libraries

**Ethersis** 

Openzeppelin

Standard and others

ERC20 ERC721 ERC1155 TheGraph **IPFS** 

Oracles and others

Chainlink Chainlink Price Feeds Chainlink VRF Chainlink Keepers

Audit

Unit testing Staging testing Slither

## About me

Telecommunications engineer by University Carlos III (Madrid) and RWTH Aachen University (Germany) with a Masters Degree on Blockchain technology, Smart Contracts and Cryptoeconomy.

Due to the hours dedicated to the theoretical study of blockchain technology and my experience as a Blockchain Engineer both designing decentralized application architectures and developing Smart Contracts I am the ideal person with whom to consult - audit - develop your idea in an effective, efficient and secure way.

## Education

MSc in Blockchain technology, Smart Contracts and Cryptoeconomy

2021 - Now

Universidad de Alcalá (Spain - remote)

MSc in Electrical Engineering, Information **Technology, and Computer Engineering** 

2021 - 2022

2017 - 2022

RWTH Aachen University (Germany)

**Telecommunications Engineering** Bachelor's degree

Universidad Carlos III de Madrid (Spain)

**Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Exchange Scholarship Awarded** 

2020 - 2021

University of Arkansas (EE.UU)

Cancelled due to COVID-19.

# **Work Experience**

TortleNinja: Blockchain Engineer

August 2022 - Now

Full-time

Development of Smart Contracts, auditing an testing. Development of backend based on API and Typescript.

Development of frontend based on Typescript, React and NodeJS.

Stack used: Solidity, Hardhat, Javascript, Ethersjs, OpenZeppelin,

TheGraph, Slither, IPFS, Typescript, React, Node, API

Quarktium: Co-Founder, Co-Ceo and Smart Contract developer

April 2022 - Now

Full-time

Cofounded Quarktium, a blockchain startup which aims to develop a sciencebased space metaverse as a key feature of the project in which I am in charge of developing all the required smart contracts.

Stack used: Solidity, Hardhat, Javascript, Ethersis, OpenZeppelin, ERC721, TheGraph, Slither, IPFS, Python

Languages

Spanish

**English** 

German

**French** 

### Smart Contract developer

Freelance

Development of Solidity Smart Contracts, unit and staging testing and audits of the developed contracts.

Stack used: Solidity, Hardhat, Javascript, Ethersjs, OpenZeppelin, ERC721, ERC20, ERC1155, TheGraph, Chainlink, ChainlinkVRF, Chainlink PriceFeeds, Chainlink Keepers, Slither, IPFS

### **UST: QA Software Engineer**

May 2021 - August 2021

March 2021 - Now

Intership

Native

Bilingual

Basic

Basic

Development of automated testing for web environments, development and testing on mobile environments, as well as research, development and implementation of new automated test environments.

Main skills: Java - XML - Cucumber - Selenium - Appium- Android Studio - AShot - Visual regressiion- Cucumber reports - Web QA - Mobile QA

## Personal projects

#### «Quarktium»

Click here to check Github repository.

Blockchain own Startup that aims to develop a science-based space metaverse which several subprojects are being developed by me:

### - Quarktium NFT Collection: UpperSky

Click here to check Github repository.

NFT collection based on an scientific background as it has transformed real Stars data from three major catalogs into NFTs.

### - Quarktium NFT Marketplace

Click here to check Github repository.

Marketplace allow users to buy and sell UpperSky NFTs with not service fee added. Royalty fees are set to  $10\,$ 

### «Racks-items»

Click here to check Github repository.

Tokenized Decentralized Commerce and MarketPlace for items using ERC1155 standard to represent them where users that owns a specific ERC721 can win items by opening a random case and can generate tickets to sell to normal users to be able to open the mentioned case.

#### «Indeliable Evidences»

Click here to check Github repository.

Timestamping Service over Bitcoin Blockchain and Prove of Ownership by ERC-721 Standard and Ethereum database implementation.

Decentralized protocol for generating content timestamps on double-chain, specifically on Bitcoin and Ethereum blockchain plus a generation of an ERC-721 token which acts as a digital prove of timestamping ownership.